<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<MyCoReWebPage><section xml:lang="de" title="Redaktion"><div class="row">
<div class="col-xs-12" lang="de">
<h1>Die Digitale Redaktion</h1>

<h2>Konzeption</h2>

<p>Im digitalen Zeitalter verändert sich auch die Publikationspraxis in paradigmatischer Weise. Neue Technologien und Methoden stehen in steter Wechselwirkung mit dem wissenschaftlichen Arbeitsprozess. Die Redaktion perspectivia.net versteht sich in dieser Konstellation als unterstützende und serviceorientierte Instanz – als <em>Digitale Redaktion</em>. Das Aufgabenfeld überspannt sich von Beratung und Vermittlung, Projektmanagement und Konzeptionierung, Auszeichnung und Anreicherung, Standardisierung und Normierung, Datenmanagement und Lizenzierung, Transformation und Archivierung, Katalogisierung und Vernetzung, Layout und Lektorat, Verteilung und Kommunikation, Schulung und Betreuung.</p>

<h2>Team</h2>

<h3>Redaktion</h3>

<ul>
	<li>Sona-Lisa Arasteh-Roodsary, Forschungsinfrastruktur OPERAS; Projekt TRIPLE</li>
	<li>Elisabeth Ernst, Forschungsinfrastruktur OPERAS; EU-Projekte</li>
	<li>Sigrid Francke, Digitale MWS-Bibliothek</li>
	<li>Dr. Eva-Maria Gerstner, bibliothekarisch-informationswissenschaftliche Services</li>
	<li>Dr. Sven Gronemeyer, Projekt "Corpus Musicae Ottomanicae"</li>
	<li>Kelly Achenbach, COESO</li>
	<li>Dr. Michael Kaiser, Referatsleitung</li>
	<li>Katrin Neumann, Koordination perspectivia.net</li>
	<li>Dr. Judith Schulte, Forschungsinfrastruktur OPERAS; EU-Projekte</li>
	<li>Dr. Nanette Rißler-Pipka, Digital Humanities und Forschungsdatenmanagement</li>
	<li>Dr. Ulrike Stockhausen, Wissenschaftskommunikation und Blogs</li>
	<li>Marlen Töpfer, Projekt OPERAS-GER</li>
	<li>Dr. Annika Wienert, DHI Warschau: Textredaktion, Lektorat, wiss. Berichtserstattungen</li>
</ul>

<h3>Wissenschaftliche Hilfskräfte</h3>

<ul>
	<li>Mia Reißner</li>
	<li>Maria Wiegel</li>
</ul>

</div>
</div>
</section>
<section xml:lang="en" title="Digital Editorial Team"><div class="row">
<div class="col-xs-12" lang="en">
<h1>The Digital Editorial Team</h1>

<h2>Concept</h2>

<p>In the digital age, publication practice is changing in a paradigmatic way. New technologies and methods are in constant interaction with the scientific process. In this context, the perspectivia.net editorial team sees itself as a supporting and service-oriented entity - as a digital editorial team. Our range of tasks spans from consulting and mediation, project management and conceptual design, mark-up and enrichment, standardisation and norming, data management and licensing, transformation and archiving, cataloguing and networking, layout and editing, distribution and communication, training and support.</p>

<h2>Team</h2>

<h3>Editorial Office</h3>

<ul>
	<li>Sona-Lisa Arasteh-Roodsary, Research Infrastructure OPERAS; Project TRIPLE</li>
	<li>Elisabeth Ernst, Research Infrastructure OPERAS; EU Projects</li>
	<li>Sigrid Francke, Digital MWS Library</li>
	<li>Dr. Eva-Maria Gerstner, Library and Information Science Services</li>
	<li>Dr. Sven Gronemeyer, Project "Corpus Musicae Ottomanicae"</li>
	<li>Kelly Achenbach, COESO</li>
	<li>Dr. Michael Kaiser, Head of Department</li>
	<li>Katrin Neumann, Coordination perspectivia.net</li>
	<li>Dr. Judith Schulte, Research Infrastructure OPERAS; EU Projects</li>
	<li>Dr. Nanette Rißler-Pipka, Digital Humanities and Research Data Management</li>
	<li>Dr. Ulrike Stockhausen, Science Communication and Blogs </li>
	<li>Marlen Töpfer, Project OPERAS-GER</li>
	<li>Dr. Annika Wienert, DHI Warschau: Text Editing, Proofreading, Academic Reporting</li>
</ul>

<h3>Research Assistants</h3>

<ul>
	<li>Mia Reißner</li>
	<li>Maria Wiegel</li>
</ul>

</div>
</div></section>
<section xml:lang="fr" title="Rédaction digitale"><div class="row">
<div class="col-xs-12" lang="fr">
<h1>La Rédaction digitale</h1>

<h2>Concept</h2>

<p>À l'ère du numérique, la pratique de la publication évolue également de manière paradigmatique. Les nouvelles technologies et méthodes interagissent constamment avec le processus de travail scientifique. Dans cette constellation, l'équipe de rédaction de perspectivia.net se considère comme une instance de soutien et de service - comme une <em>équipe de rédaction digitale</em>. L'éventail des tâches s'étend du conseil et de la médiation à la gestion de projet et au design conceptuel, en passant par le balisage et l'enrichissement, la normalisation et la standardisation, la gestion des données et les licences, la transformation et l'archivage, le catalogage et la mise en réseau, la mise en page et l'édition, la distribution et la communication, la formation et le soutien.</p>

<h2>Équipe</h2>

<h3>Rédaction</h3>

<ul>
	<li>Sona-Lisa Arasteh-Roodsary, Research Infrastructure OPERAS; Project TRIPLE</li>
	<li>Elisabeth Ernst, Research Infrastructure OPERAS; EU Projects</li>
	<li>Sigrid Francke, Bibliothèque digitale de la MWS</li>
	<li>Dr. Eva-Maria Gerstner, Library and Information Science Services</li>
	<li>Dr. Sven Gronemeyer, Project "Corpus Musicae Ottomanicae"</li>
	<li>Kelly Achenbach, COESO</li>
	<li>Dr. Michael Kaiser, Head of Department</li>
	<li>Katrin Neumann, Coordination perspectivia.net</li>
	<li>Dr. Judith Schulte, Research Infrastructure OPERAS; EU Projects</li>
	<li>Dr. Nanette Rißler-Pipka, Digital Humanities et Research Data Management</li>
	<li>Dr. Ulrike Stockhausen, Science Communication and Blogs </li>
	<li>Marlen Töpfer, Project OPERAS-GER</li>
	<li>Dr. Annika Wienert, DHI Warschau: Text Editing, Proofreading, Academic Reporting</li>
</ul>

<h3>Assistants de recherche</h3>

<ul>
	<li>Mia Reißner</li>
	<li>Maria Wiegel</li>
</ul>

</div>
</div>
</section>
<meta><log lastEditor="mwiegel" date="2024-01-24" time="12:14" /></meta></MyCoReWebPage>
