<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<MyCoReWebPage><section xml:lang="de" title="Redaktion"><div class="row">
<div class="col-xs-12" lang="de">
<h1>Die Digitale Redaktion</h1>
<h2>Konzeption</h2>
<p>Im digitalen Zeitalter verändert sich auch die Publikationspraxis in paradigmatischer Weise. Neue Technologien und Methoden stehen in steter Wechselwirkung mit dem wissenschaftlichen Arbeitsprozess. In dieser Konstellation versteht sich die Redaktion perspectivia.net als unterstützende und serviceorientierte Instanz – als Digitale Redaktion. Das Aufgabenfeld umfasst Beratung und Vermittlung, Projektmanagement und Konzeptionierung, Standardisierung und Normierung, Datenmanagement und Lizenzierung, Transformation und Archivierung, Katalogisierung und Vernetzung, Verteilung und Kommunikation sowie Schulung und Betreuung.</p>
<p>Kontakt: <a href="mailto:perspectivia@maxweberstiftung.de">perspectivia@MaxWeberStiftung.de</a></p>
<h2>Team</h2>
<ul>
<li>Dr. Michael Kaiser, Referatsleitung</li>
</ul>
<h3>Publikationsplattform perspectivia.net</h3>
<ul>
<li>Katrin Neumann, Koordination digitale Publikationen, perspectivia.net, MWS-Bibliographie</li>
</ul>
<h3>Quelleneditionen, Digital Humanities und Forschungsdatenmanagement</h3>
<ul>
<li>Dr. Eva-Maria Gerstner, bibliothekarisch-informationswissenschaftliche Services, RDMO</li>
<li>Dr. Sven Gronemeyer, Projekt <a href="https://corpus-musicae-ottomanicae.de/content/index.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener">"Corpus Musicae Ottomanicae"</a></li>
<li>Dr. Nanette Rißler-Pipka, Koordination Quelleneditionen (<a href="https://qed.perspectivia.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">QED</a>), Digital Humanities und Forschungsdatenmanagement, NFDI</li>
</ul>
<h3>Koordination übergreifende Bibliotheksdienste</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sigrid Francke, <a href="https://discovery.maxweberstiftung.de/vufind/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Digitale MWS-Bibliothek</a></li>
</ul>
<h3>Wissenschaftliche Hilfskräfte</h3>
<ul>
<li>Mia Reißner</li>
<li>Maria Wiegel</li>
</ul>
<h3>Projekte und Services der nationalen, europäischen Forschungsinfrastrukturen</h3>
<ul>
<li>Kelly Achenbach, Forschungsinfrastruktur <a href="https://operas-eu.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OPERAS</a>; Projekt CRAFT-OA</li>
<li>Dr. Sona-Lisa Arasteh-Roodsary, Forschungsinfrastruktur <a href="https://operas-eu.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OPERAS</a>; Projekt LUMEN</li>
<li>Léa Foumany, Forschungsinfrastruktur <a href="https://operas-eu.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OPERAS</a>; Projekt LUMEN</li>
<li>Dr. Ulrike Stockhausen, Wissenschaftskommunikation und <a href="https://de.hypotheses.org/community-management" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blogs</a></li>
<li>Marlen Töpfer, Forschungsinfrastruktur <a href="https://operas-eu.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OPERAS</a>; EU-Projekte</li>
<li>Dr. Renate Voget, Servicestelle Diamond Open Access (<a href="https://diamond-open-access.de/en/sedoa/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SeDOA</a>)</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div></section><section xml:lang="en" title="Digital Editorial Team"><div class="row">
<div class="col-xs-12" lang="en">
<h1>The Digital Editorial Team</h1>
<h2>Concept</h2>
<p>In the digital age, publication practices are undergoing a paradigm shift. New technologies and methods are in constant interplay with academic research. In this context, the perspectivia.net editorial team sees itself as a provider of customised support – as a digital editorial team. We offer a wide range of services, including consulting and guidance, project management and concept design, development and application of standards, data management and licensing, transformation and archiving, cataloguing and networking, distribution and communication, training and ongoing assistance.</p>
<p>Contact: <a href="mailto:perspectivia@MaxWeberStiftung.de">perspectivia@MaxWeberStiftung.de</a></p>
<h2>Team</h2>
<ul>
<li>Dr. Michael Kaiser, Head of Department</li>
</ul>
<h3>perspectivia.net Publication Platform</h3>
<ul>
<li>Katrin Neumann, Coordination Digital Publications, perspectivia.net, MWS-Bibliography</li>
</ul>
<h3>Source Editions, Digital Humanities and Research Data Management</h3>
<ul>
<li>Dr. Eva-Maria Gerstner, Library and Information Science Services, RDMO</li>
<li>Dr. Sven Gronemeyer, Project <a href="https://corpus-musicae-ottomanicae.de/content/index.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener">"Corpus Musicae Ottomanicae"</a></li>
<li>Dr. Nanette Rißler-Pipka, Coordination of Source Editions (<a href="https://qed.perspectivia.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">QED</a>), Digital Humanities and Research Data Management, NFDI</li>
</ul>
<h3>Coordination of Cross-Library Services</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sigrid Francke, <a href="https://discovery.maxweberstiftung.de/vufind/?lng=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MWS Digital Library</a></li>
</ul>
<h3>Academic assistants </h3>
<ul>
<li>Mia Reißner</li>
<li>Maria Wiegel</li>
</ul>
<h3>National and European Research Infrastructure Projects and Services</h3>
<ul>
<li>Kelly Achenbach, Research Infrastructure <a href="https://operas-eu.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OPERAS</a>; Project CRAFT-OA</li>
<li>Dr. Sona-Lisa Arasteh-Roodsary, Research Infrastructure <a href="https://operas-eu.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OPERAS</a>; Project LUMEN </li>
<li>Léa Foumany, Research Infrastructure <a href="https://operas-eu.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OPERAS</a>; Project LUMEN </li>
<li>Dr. Ulrike Stockhausen, Scholarly Communication and <a href="https://de.hypotheses.org/community-management" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blogs </a></li>
<li>Marlen Töpfer, Research Infrastructure <a href="https://operas-eu.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OPERAS</a>; EU Projects </li>
<li>Dr. Renate Voget, Diamond Open Access Service Point (<a href="https://diamond-open-access.de/en/sedoa/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SeDOA</a>) </li>
</ul>
</div>
</div></section><section xml:lang="fr" title="Rédaction digitale"><div class="row">
<div class="col-xs-12" lang="fr">
<h1>La Rédaction digitale</h1>
<h2>Concept</h2>
<p>À l'ère du numérique, la pratique de la publication évolue également de manière paradigmatique. Les nouvelles technologies et méthodes sont en interaction constante avec la recherche académique. Dans ce contexte, l'équipe de rédaction de perspectivia.net se veut une instance de soutien et de service - comme une équipe de rédaction numérique. Les services comprennent le conseil et l'accompagnement, la gestion de projets et à la conceptualisation, le développement et l'application de standards, la gestion des données et des licences, la transformation et l'archivage, le catalogage et la mise en réseau, la diffusion et la communication, la formation et l'assistance continue.</p>
<p>Contact : <a href="mailto:perspectivia@MaxWeberStiftung.de">perspectivia@MaxWeberStiftung.de</a></p>
<h2>Équipe</h2>
<ul>
<li>Dr. Michael Kaiser, Chef de département</li>
</ul>
<h3>Plateforme de publication perspectivia.net</h3>
<ul>
<li>Katrin Neumann, Coordination Publications numériques, perspectivia.net, Bibliographie MWS</li>
</ul>
<h3>Éditions de sources numériques, Digital Humanities et gestion des données de recherche</h3>
<ul>
<li>Dr. Eva-Maria Gerstner, Services bibliothéconomiques et informationnels, RDMO </li>
<li>Dr. Sven Gronemeyer, Projet <a href="https://corpus-musicae-ottomanicae.de/content/index.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener">« Corpus Musicae Ottomanicae »</a></li>
<li>Dr. Nanette Rißler-Pipka, Coordination des éditions de sources numériques (<a href="https://qed.perspectivia.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">QED</a>), Digital Humanities et gestion des données de recherche, NFDI <br /></li>
</ul>
<h3>Coordination des services inter-bibliothèques</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sigrid Francke, <a href="https://discovery.maxweberstiftung.de/vufind/?lng=fr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bibliothèque MWS numérique </a></li>
</ul>
<h3>Assistants scientifiques</h3>
<ul>
<li>Mia Reißner </li>
<li>Maria Wiegel<br /></li>
</ul>
<h3>Projets et Services des Infrastructures de Recherche Nationales et Européennes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Kelly Achenbach, Infrastructure de recherche <a href="https://operas-eu.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OPERAS</a>; Projet CRAFT-OA </li>
<li>Dr. Sona-Lisa Arasteh-Roodsary, Infrastructure de recherche <a href="https://operas-eu.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OPERAS</a>; Projet LUMEN </li>
<li>Léa Foumany, Infrastructure de recherche <a href="https://operas-eu.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OPERAS</a>; Projet LUMEN </li>
<li>Dr. Ulrike Stockhausen, Communication scientifique et <a href="https://de.hypotheses.org/community-management" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blogs</a></li>
<li>Marlen Töpfer, Infrastructure de recherche <a href="https://operas-eu.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OPERAS</a>; Projets UE </li>
<li>Dr. Renate Voget, Responsable Animation Réseau Diamond Open Access (<a href="https://diamond-open-access.de/en/sedoa/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SeDOA</a>) <br /></li>
</ul>
<p />
</div>
</div></section><meta><log lastEditor="administrator" date="2025-09-05" time="12:34" /></meta></MyCoReWebPage>
