<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<MyCoReWebPage><section xml:lang="de" title="Impressum"><div class="row">
<div class="col-md-10" lang="de">
<h2>Impressum</h2>

<p>Die elektronische Publikationsplattform perspectivia.net ist ein nicht-kommerzieller Dienst der <a class="external-link" href="http://www.maxweberstiftung.de/startseite.html">Max Weber Stiftung – Deutsche Geisteswissenschaftliche Institute im Ausland</a>.</p>

<h3>Leitung</h3>

<p>Dr. Michael Kaiser<br />
Max Weber Stiftung – Deutsche Geisteswissenschaftliche Institute im Ausland<br />
Rheinallee 6<br />
D-53173 Bonn<br />
Telefon +49 (0)228 37786-24<br />
E-Mail kaiser(at)maxweberstiftung.de<br />
<br />
Die Max Weber Stiftung wird gefördert durch das Bundesministerium für Bildung und Forschung (BMBF)</p>

<h3>Haftung</h3>

<p><i>perspectivia.net</i> publiziert Forschungsergebnisse und Informationen auf dieser Website nach bestem Wissen und sorgfältiger Kontrolle der Inhalte. Eine Gewähr für Aktualität, Richtigkeit und Vollständigkeit der auf der Website veröffentlichten Informationen und Verweise kann aufgrund ständiger Aktualisierungen der Website nicht übernommen werden. Eine Haftung für Vermögensschäden oder Vermögensfolgeschäden, die durch Nutzung von Angeboten auf der Website entstehen, ist ausgeschlossen, sofern <i>perspectivia.net</i> den Eintritt solcher Schäden nicht grob fahrlässig oder vorsätzlich verursacht hat.<br />
Externe Links, auf die <i>perspectivia.net</i> keinen Einfluss hat, haben informativen Charakter und geben den Inhalt und die Meinung der jeweiligen Anbieter dieser Seiten wieder. <i>perspectivia.net</i> verweist auf solche Seiten nur, ohne sich den Inhalt oder die Aussagen dieser Seiten zueigen zu machen. Für eventuelle Rechtsverletzungen auf diesen Seiten übernehmen wir daher keine Haftung. Für den Inhalt dieser verlinkten Seiten sind ausschließlich deren Betreiber verantwortlich.<br />
Soweit inhaltliche oder sachliche Fehler auf dieser Website bemerkt werden, bitten wir um eine E-Mail, um eine Richtigstellung vornehmen zu können. Bei inhaltlichen oder technischen Fehlern in genuin elektronisch oder retrodigitalisiert zur Verfügung gestellten Publikationen wenden Sie sich bitte zusätzlich direkt an die jeweilige Lokalredaktion oder an die Zentralredaktion in Bonn.</p>

<h3>Copyright</h3>

<p>Sämtliche Inhalte dieser Website sind urheberrechtlich geschützt. Unerlaubte Verwendung, Reproduktion oder Weitergabe einzelner Inhalte oder Bilder können sowohl zivil- als auch strafrechtlich verfolgt werden.<br />
Die Befugnis zur Nutzung aller auf <i>perspectivia.net</i> bereitgestellten Inhalte (Ausnahme: retrodigitalisierte Inhalte, d.h. bereits gedruckt publizierte und hier durch Scan bereitgestellte Inhalte) regelt die CC-Lizenz, soweit nicht ein ausdrücklicher entgegenstehender Rechtevorbehalt beim jeweiligen Inhalt erfolgte. Der Lizenztext ist <a class="external-link" href="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creative_Commons">hier</a> im Internet abrufbar. Achtung! Für einzelne Inhalte können – je nach Zeitpunkt der Veröffentlichung – unterschiedliche CC-Lizenzbedingungen gelten. Die jeweils gültige CC-Lizenz wird im Zusammenhang mit dem jeweiligen Inhalt gesondert verlinkt. Die auf <i>perspectivia.net</i> retrodigitalisiert bereitgestellten Inhalte unterliegen dem Urheberrechtsmodell.<br />
<br />
Eine Verlinkung der Homepage von <i>perspectivia.net</i> darf vorgenommen werden und ist sogar ausdrücklich erwünscht. Bitte verwenden Sie hierfür das hier bereitgestellte Logo.</p>

<p><img alt="" src="../../images/logos/perspectivia_Logo_quer_neu.png" style="width: 315px; height: 72px;" /></p>

<p><img alt="" src="../../images/logos/perspectivia_logo_complete.png" style="width: 116px; height: 200px;" /></p>

<h3>Markeneintrag</h3>

<p>perspectivia.net ist eine beim HABM / OHIM eingetragene Gemeinschaftsmarke Nr. 010 827 384.</p>
</div>
</div>
</section><section xml:lang="en" title="Imprint"><div class="row">
<div class="col-md-10" lang="en">
<h2>Imprint</h2>

<p>The electronic publication platform perspectivia.net is a non-commercial service of the <a class="external-link" href="http://www.maxweberstiftung.de/startseite.html">Max Weber Stiftung – Foundation German Humanities Institutes Abroad</a>.</p>

<h3>Head</h3>

<p>Dr. Michael Kaiser<br />
Max Weber Stiftung – Foundation German Humanities Institutes Abroad<br />
Rheinallee 6<br />
D-53173 Bonn<br />
Phone +49 (0)228 37786-24<br />
E-Mail kaiser(at)maxweberstiftung.de<br />
<br />
The Max Weber Foundation is funded by the Federal Ministry of Education and Research (BMBF)</p>

<h3>Liability</h3>

<p><i>perspectivia.net</i> publishes research results and information on this website to the best of its knowledge and careful control of the content. No guarantee can be given for the topicality, correctness and completeness of the information and references published on the website due to constant updating of the website. Liability for financial loss or consequential financial loss arising from the use of offers on the website is excluded, unless <em>perspectivia.net</em> has caused the occurrence of such loss or damage through gross negligence or wilful misconduct.<br />
External links, over which <i>perspectivia.net</i> has no influence, are of an informative nature and reflect the content and opinion of the respective providers of these sites. perspectivia.net only refers to such sites without adopting the content or statements of these sites. We therefore accept no liability for any legal infringements on these pages. The operators of these linked sites are solely responsible for their content.<br />
If errors of content or fact are noticed on this website, please send us an e-mail so that we can correct them. In the event of errors in content or technical errors in publications made available in electronic or retro-digital form, please also contact the respective local editorial office or the central editorial office in Bonn directly.</p>

<h3>Copyright</h3>

<p>All contents of this website are protected by copyright. Unauthorised use, reproduction or dissemination of individual contents or images may be prosecuted under both civil and criminal law.<br />
The authorisation to use all content provided on <em>perspectivia.net</em> (exception: retro-digitised content, i.e. content already published in print and made available here by scanning) is governed by the CC licence, unless an explicit reservation of rights to the contrary has been made for the respective content. The licence text is available <a class="external-link" href="https://creativecommons.org/about/cclicenses/">here</a> on the Internet. Attention! Depending on the time of publication, different CC licence conditions may apply to individual items of content. The respective valid CC licence is linked separately in connection with the respective content. The content provided on <em>perspectivia.net</em> retrodigitised is subject to the copyright model.<br />
<br />
Linking to the <em>perspectivia.net</em> homepage is permitted and even expressly desired. Please use the logo provided here for this purpose.</p>

<p><img alt="" src="../../images/logos/perspectivia_Logo_quer_neu.png" style="width: 315px; height: 72px;" /></p>

<p><img alt="" src="../../images/logos/perspectivia_logo_complete.png" style="width: 116px; height: 200px;" /></p>

<h3>Trademark entry</h3>

<p><em>perspectivia.net</em> is a Community trade mark registered at HABM / OHIM No. 010 827 384.</p>
</div>
</div>
</section><section xml:lang="fr" title="Crédits"><div class="row">
<div class="col-md-10" lang="fr">
<h2>Crédits</h2>

<p>La plateforme de publication électronique perspectivia.net est un service non commercial de la <a class="external-link" href="http://www.maxweberstiftung.de/startseite.html">Fondation Max-Weber</a>.</p>

<h3>Direction</h3>

<p>Dr. Michael Kaiser<br />
Fondation Max-Weber<br />
Rheinallee 6<br />
D-53173 Bonn<br />
Téléphone +49 (0)228 37786-24<br />
E-Mail kaiser(at)maxweberstiftung.de<br />
<br />
La Fondation Max-Weber est financée par le ministère fédéral allemand de l'éducation et de la recherche (BMBF)</p>

<h3>Responsabilité civile</h3>

<p><em>perspectivia.net</em> publie sur ce site des résultats de recherche et des informations au mieux de ses connaissances et en contrôlant soigneusement le contenu. En raison des mises à jour constantes du site, aucune garantie ne peut être donnée quant à l'actualité, l'exactitude et l'exhaustivité des informations et des références publiées sur le site. La responsabilité pour les pertes financières ou les pertes financières consécutives résultant de l'utilisation des offres du site web est exclue, à moins que <em>perspectivia.net</em> n'ait provoqué la survenance de tels dommages par négligence grave ou intentionnellement.<br />
Les liens externes, sur lesquels<em> perspectivia.net</em> n'a aucune influence, ont un caractère informatif et reflètent le contenu et l'opinion des fournisseurs respectifs de ces sites. <em>perspectivia.net</em> ne fait que renvoyer à ces sites sans adopter le contenu ou les déclarations de ces sites. Nous déclinons donc toute responsabilité en cas d'infraction à la loi sur ces sites. Les opérateurs de ces sites liés sont seuls responsables de leur contenu.<br />
Si vous constatez des erreurs de contenu ou de fait sur ce site, veuillez nous envoyer un e-mail afin que nous puissions les corriger. En cas d'erreurs de contenu ou d'erreurs techniques dans les publications mises à disposition sous forme purement électronique ou rétro-numérisée, veuillez également vous adresser directement à la rédaction locale concernée ou à la rédaction centrale de Bonn.</p>

<h3>Copyright</h3>

<p>L'ensemble du contenu de ce site web est protégé par le droit d'auteur. L'utilisation, la reproduction ou la distribution non autorisée de contenus individuels ou d'images peut faire l'objet de poursuites tant au civil qu'au pénal.<br />
Le droit d'utilisation de tous les contenus mis à disposition sur <em>perspectivia.net</em> (à l'exception des contenus rétro-digitalisés, c'est-à-dire des contenus déjà publiés en version imprimée et mis à disposition ici par numérisation) est régi par la licence CC, sauf si une réserve de droits contraire explicite a été faite pour le contenu respectif. Le texte de la licence est disponible <a class="external-link" href="https://creativecommons.org/about/cclicenses/">ici</a> sur Internet. Attention ! Selon le moment de la publication, différentes conditions de licence CC peuvent s'appliquer à des éléments de contenu individuels. La licence CC applicable est liée séparément au contenu respectif. Le contenu fourni sur <em>perspectivia.net</em> retrodigitised est soumis au modèle du droit d'auteur.<br />
<br />
La création de liens vers la page d'accueil de <em>perspectivia.net</em> est autorisée et même expressément souhaitée. Veuillez utiliser le logo fourni ici à cette fin.</p>

<p><img alt="" src="../../images/logos/perspectivia_Logo_quer_neu.png" style="width: 315px; height: 72px;" /></p>

<p><img alt="" src="../../images/logos/perspectivia_logo_complete.png" style="width: 116px; height: 200px;" /></p>

<h3>Entrée de la marque</h3>

<p><em>perspectivia.net</em> est une marque communautaire enregistrée auprès de l'HABM / OHIM No. 010 827 384.</p>
</div>
</div>
</section><meta><log lastEditor="agerber" date="2021-05-31" time="11:18" /></meta></MyCoReWebPage>
